Thomas Seropian

French nationality, Indefinite leave to remain Currently based in London, United Kingdom

thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

Senior / Lead Software Engineer

Profile

I am a senior technologist, with more than a decade experience managing complex technology projects for various types of organisations. I am head of engineering for a med-tech startup, delivering medical applications for both public and private clients. I have been technology lead for an international media group, managing content web applications and infrastructure for supporting millions of unique monthly users. Prior to that, I built and managing a team of 5 technologists for a non profit organisation in London and remotely.

Skill set: Managing web applications, leading technical teams. System designing. Leadership, communication with technical and non-technical audiences. Strong sense of innovation. Design and creation of user stories. Research, prototyping. Flexibility. Project management. Hiring, mentoring and performance management.

Work experience

Head of Engineering for a med-tech startup

Skin Analytics, London, United Kingdom – October 2017 to present (<u>www.skin-analytics.com</u>)

ightarrow Responsible for clients, internal and commercial applications and infrastructures

Designing, defining roadmaps, scoping new features and product requirements. Managing infrastructure, including release processes and improvements. Hiring and leading technical team (both in house and contractors), day to day management, code reviews and testing with a focus on security.

Leading design and delivery of a commercial Software as Medical Device (IEC 62304) cloud based API.

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, Angular 7, TypeScript, React Native, CouchDB, MySQL, Docker, Ansible, Nginx

Technical Lead (contract based) for an international online media publishing group **Jamie Oliver,** London, United Kingdom – February to September 2017 (www.jamieoliver.com)

- → Responsible for infrastructure and web applications supporting Jamie's online presence.

 Designing, defining roadmaps, scoping and delivering new features and APIs. Managing AWS based infrastructure, including release processes, optimisations and improvements.
- → <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, PHP (Laravel), RESTful APIs, Redis, Solr, , Vue.js, WordPress, Varnish.

Mentor and Advisor, since 2018

- → Mentoring for the tech lead curriculum for the main french online education platform Open Classrooms
- → Coach and advisor for a startup challenge about <u>Blockchain and social impact</u>

Technology Manager for an international NGO

Internews London, United Kingdom – April 2015 to December 2016 (www.internews.org)

- → Leading the design, development and delivery of innovation and technology components

 Working with a multidisciplinary team supporting local start-ups among the most repressive regimes.

 Leading on delivering news publishing apps. Managing activities' budgets. Speaking at conferences and events

 → Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects (8 countries)

 Overseeing recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 4 technologists. Ensuring planning, setting priorities, agreeing detailed work plans, budgets and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members. Agile delivery. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap. Strong focus on scalability, quality & security.
- → <u>Technology:</u> Wordpress, Drupal (7/8), PHP MVC, Node.js, Ansible, Nginx, OpenVPN, encryption.

Freelance Consultant in open source technologies Self-Employed London, United Kingdom – April 2014 to September 2015 (www.seropian.io)

- → Designing & developing web applications and prototypes for various range of clients
- → Areas of work: Drupal, E-Commerce, intranet applications, Infrastructure management.

Designed and built a subscription-based application, including automated online payments. Agile Prototyping. Developed Intranet and extranet applications including import/export modules for a booking agent. Defined and prioritized user stories in close collaboration with different team members.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Node.js, Drupal 7, Drush, Github, Selenium HQ, Vagrant, RESTful APIs.

ICT Projects Manager / Web Application Engineer for an international NGO Internews Paris, France / London, United Kingdom - March 2009 to March 2014 (www.internews.eu)

→ On-line freedom of expression, support of local media, digital security

Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications, custom modules. Integration with social network (Twitter, Facebook) APIs. Writing documentation for users. Managing localizations, training & support

Writing user stories & specifications. Managing external contractors and developers, resources & infrastructures: Deployment and monitoring of servers, secure hosting & video platforms. Building, delivering and facilitating trainings & trainers on ICT topics. Training of trainers on website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA)

→ <u>Technology</u>: Drupal, Mediawiki, XML/JSON, PHP (OOP, MVC), MySQL, Solr, AWS, Collectd, Vagrant, Nginx.

Software Engineer for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France – February 2008 to January 2009 (www.hellotipi.com)

- → Designed, developed and implemented new features for the service.

 Video sharing. Photo tagging. Revamped registration process. Multilingual support. Managed client support.
- → <u>Technology</u>: Debian, Apache, MySQL, PHP5 (OOP, MVC), XML, Jquery, Ffmpeg.

ICT Projects Manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia - March 2006 to September 2007 (www.kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer trainings in youth training centres. Developed activities in 2 major cities. Managed recruitment of local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs. Participated to feasibility studies & design for countrywide projects.

Assistant Projects Manager for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France – March 2005 to February 2006 (www.valeo.com) Designed & implemented tools for course supports creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

Education

MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation

Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (www.esiea.fr).

 \rightarrow Graduated with first class honours.

Foreign languages

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner